# CHINMAY ANAND PANDA

(+91) 8260269393 | official chinmay an and @gmail.com | in chinmay - an and - panda

### **Profile Summary**

Steering cloud-based solutions, leverages AWS Cloud, translating academic insights from my BTech at Silicon Institute of Technology into tangible technological advancements. A collaborative spirit and a commitment to continual growth define our work ethos. With certifications like the AWS Solutions Architect Associate possess practical expertise working with AWS, Terraform, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, Python, and GitHub in the industry.

### Work Experience

#### Accolite Digital (2 years)

Banaalore

Senior Software Engineer

October 2023 - May 2024

- Designing cloud systems: Design, Optimize and deploy automated, fault tolerant, highly available, secure cloud architecture solutions.
- · Modernizations and Migration: Modernize and migrate out old architecture to cloud native solutions that at 10x faster, 5x more secure and scalable with near zero downtime.
- For the top US stock broker, the database layer was successfully moved to a cloud-native solution.
- Developed and implemented cloud-based solutions that maintain HIPAA compliance while outperforming their current on-premise machine by 95%.
- Reduced guery times by 75% by managing, optimizing, and automating particular aspects of the containerized backend hosted on AWS, Azure and GCP for an AI and ML team.
- · Developed a dependable automated backup solution that bolsters cloud resources for secure cloud compliance and performs company-wide backups.

Software Engineer

- May 2022 October 2023 · Developed, constructed, and implemented a centralized CI/CD pipeline that uses ECS clusters to deploy team code.
- · Designed and developed a system that uses native AWS cloud technologies to deploy any 2-tier or 3-tier application code, with Terraform enabling automated infrastructure development.
- Constructed an Infrastructure as a Code solution that is ready for deployment and that generates dashboards for cloudwatch monitoring that support multiple accounts and regions.

**Accolite Digital** Remote

Software Engineer Intern INTERN August 2021- May 2022

- Collaborated on redesigning cloud infrastructure for US based healthcare firm.
- Transformed designs of a CI/CD pipeline for a product team of a UK based banking firm.

## **Projects**

#### **AWS ECS Terraform Accelerator**

AWS (ECS, CI/CD Suite, Lamdba, ECR), Terraform

Containerized deployment for multi-tier applications

- Designed and developed a ready-to-use terraform module that creates CI/CD pipeline in AWS for any multi-tier application using ECS.
- Supports advanced configurability options such as CloudWatch monitoring, automated backups.

#### AWS CloudWatch Terraform Accelerator

AWS (CloudWatch, IAM, Organizations), Terraform

Ready to deploy laaC module that creates monitoring for all resources

- Developed terraform module that creates centralized CloudWatch monitoring dashboard for AWS Accounts in an organization with multiregion monitoring capabilities.
- Uses tag-based monitoring to avoid any manual attaching of resources once launched.

### **Technical Skills**

Strongest Areas AWS – Associate Solutions Architect, Data Structures, Algorithms

**Programming Languages** C/C++, JavaScript, Python, Java

Libraries/Frameworks React.js, Express.js, Git, Node.js, Kubernetes, Docker, HTML5, CSS

**Database** MongoDB, Firebase, PostgreSQL

**Platforms** AWS, Azure

### **Education**

#### Silicon Institute of Technology

Bhubaneswar, India

B.Tech iN COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEER June. 2018 - May. 2022

• 8.70/10

# Certifications